

SUMIT MAHANAG



+91 9918733576 +91 7052089090

sumit.en1997@gmail.com



<u>sumit-</u> <u>mahanag@linkedin.com</u>

roodymiike@github.com

roodymike.github.io

PROPOSITION

 According to the Job description your requirement is for a high performing active candidate which can mold himself/herself and be a team player, with customer centricity. I think I am a perfect candidate for the same as my prior experience and qualification suggests the same.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

- To better understand the needs of my customers and seek to improve myself providing a cognitive approach to mutual betterment.
- To achieve a customer centric sustainability and skills.

PROJECTS IN DESIGN

- Full-Stack message API with Kafka,
 Spring, AMQ (In Research).
- Cross platform portfolio in Flutter (In Development)
- Development of Package Orientation Provider for most efficient orientation of packages to improve usage of space and increase in revenue using Machine learning (In Research).

SKILLS Linux Java Spring Red Hat AMQ Xamarin Forms

Exploring tech blogs Designing illustrations Gaming Robotics Music production

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of technology

(Year 2019)

United Institute of Technology, Prayagraj (AKTU)

Specialization in Electrical and Electronics Engineering securing 79.83% marks (1st Division HONS)

<u>Senior secondary</u>

(Year 2015)

(Year 2013)

St. Mary's Convent School, Ghoorpur (CBSE)

Specialization in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematic with 69% marks.

<u>High school</u>
Bethany Convent School, Allahabad (CBSE)

Specialization in Science and Mathematics with 74% marks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

(24th June 2020 – till date)

Wipro Technologies, Hyderabad

- Developed Full-Stack messaging application using Spring boot, Red Hat AMQ, HTML5 and Xamarin resulting in reduced server downtime and data loss, also the architecture's performance improved by 12%.
- Applied automations for projects to help mitigate the manual work, done by other developers, resulting in increased operational efficiency by 8%.
- Working as a full-time Xamarin, developer implementing log analysis, fixing defects, bugs and research stories, improving system stability and reduction in defect count by 50%.

<u>Freelance Software Engineer</u>

(Aug 2016 - Feb 2019)

Prayagraj

Solely responsible for development, deployment, scaling of Web and Mobile Applications for small scale business using Linux, AWS, Cloudflare, HTML, Flutter and Adobe Illustrator which resulted in increased customer's revenue and satisfaction.

<u>Intern</u>

(June 2018 – Aug 2018)

HAL, Lucknow

- Got an Aerospace Industry **experience in Avionics and ERP** on its latest offerings as combat aircraft **and its system design**.
- Helped me improve and understand the aspects of system design and customer satisfaction by managing inventory, schedules, and implementation of Kaizen for quality.

ENDORSED PROJECTS

Open Source Messaging API

(4-7 Months)

Developer, Tester and Maintainer

 Implemented Spring, Red Hat AMQ as a robust, efficient replacement to existing Kazzing library, improving performance by 12%, that reduced server load, unresponsiveness, and data loss.

VR Guru

(3 Months)

Developer, Tester

 Implemented Unity (C#) to create an intuitive learning experience for clients, allowing users to experience business flows virtually, resulting in better retention and reduced training turnover by 31%

Spring CRUD API

(7-8 Days)

Developer

• Implemented **Spring**, **Hibernate**, **Maven** to design API for **CRUD Operations** in **DB**.

Smart Helmet (7-8 Days)

Developer

Implemented Android Auto, PHP, Linux, Raspberry, Python and Google services to design application, monitoring vitals of Bike and Rider to ensure utmost safety and theft protection.

POSITIONS AND RESPONSIBILITIES

<u>Rotaract</u>

Technical Lead

 Worked as a Lead of 3 team members designing intuitive webpages and illustration for better campaigning resulting in better reach, increased assimilation, and increased donations of 32%.

Freelance Software Developer

Owne

Worked as a developer for freelancing projects with customer centricity and customer satisfaction in mind, improving my reach and better understanding of my customer's needs.

ACHIEVEMENTS / AWARDS / CO-SCHOLASTIC ACHIVEMENTS

- One of top 500 competitors in state at HackwithInfy, organized by Infosys, 2018.
- Work beyond duty awarded by clients at Wipro Technologies.
- Secured 2nd position for my Team in Robowars at IIT Allahabad in 2018